<Document>
  # Core Rule 3 - Roleplay Standards

  Station 7 is a Medium Roleplay (MRP) server. This means you are expected to play a character — not just a player controlling a body.

  ## What MRP Means at Station7

  You should have a character with a role, a purpose, and a reason to be on the station. Your character knows what their job is and operates within the bounds of that job and their experience.

  You do not need to be serious all the time. Humorous and lighthearted characters are welcome, as long as they don't negatively interfere with other players experience.

  ## What This Looks Like In Practice

  - Play your role. A chef cooks. An engineer fixes things. You can interact with the rest of the station, but your job is your anchor.
  - Suddenly deciding to destroy random things or kill random players without context is not acceptable.
  - Your character knows what they know. A janitor wasn't trained in surgery. A botanist doesn't inherently know how to hack an airlock.
    - Playing unfulfilled jobs in low-pop instances is exempt from this.
  - React to the round as your character would, not as a player who has seen it all before.
  - Speak and act as your character would — not as yourself.
  - Antagonists have more freedom, but should still have some reason behind their actions.
  - Do not use out-of-character knowledge to influence your in-character decisions (metagaming).
  - Do not Powergame (immediately running to the location of a role unrelated to yours and stealing "x" equipment).
  - Do not use LOOC or OOC to share information about the current round, such as antag identities or your location.
  - You may break character when assisting players in learning mechanics or answering meta questions.

  LOOC and OOC as implied are out of character and exempt from most restrictions, so long as they do not influence gameplay (see above).

  ## What MRP Is Not

  MRP is not HRP (High Roleplay). You are not required to write or maintain a deep backstory. You just need to be a person on a space station doing your job, reacting to the world around you, and not breaking immersion for others without cause.
</Document>
